Guide to the James A. Perkins papers, 1941-1997.
Perkins, James A. papers, 1941-1997
- Series III. Cornell Presidency
  - Cornell Commencement, June 13, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Selective Service on Campus Faculty Petition, May 1966 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Study of Rising Costs at Ten Universities, September 1967 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Proposal for National Commission on Higher Ed. For Negro (Cornell University), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Cornell Convocation (New York), March 9, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Report of the Special Cornell University Commission of April, April 1968 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Statements from Board of Trustees (Cornell University crisis), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - James Perkins' statements (Cornell University crisis), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Minutes of Faculty Meetings (Cornell University crisis), April-May 1969 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Executive Staff Chronology (Cornell University crisis), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Cornell University News Bureau Chronology, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Press Clippings (Cornell University crisis), 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Press Clippings (Cornell University crisis), April 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Willard Straight Hall (Cornell University), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - James Perkins' personal answers to correspondence (Cornell University crisis), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Security, Police Report (Cornell University Crisis), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - President's Commission on Student Involvement in Decision Making- report (Cornell University Crisis), May 26, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Report on Undergraduate Education (Cornell University), October 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - James Perkins' resignation (Cornell University), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Responses to James Perkins' resignation (Cornell University), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence (Cornell University), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence Cornell University), 1970-1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence (Cornell University), 1970-1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - General Materials (Cornell University), 1974-1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Alumni News, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - African-American Studies/ relations with black students (Cornell University) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Special Educational Projects (Cornell University) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Social Functions- memorabilia (Cornell University) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Social Functions/ photographs (Cornell University) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - List of Trips (Cornell Years), 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Cornell Trustees, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Series IV. International Council for Educational Development
  - ICED & Ford Foundation, May 1972-December 1975 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - ICED & Ford Foundation, December 1975-January 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - ICED- Italy Meeting, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - German-American Conference on University & Research Problems- Villa Hugel, Essen, July 1972 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - ICED- Europe, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - ICED-Access to Higher Education Report, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - ICED- Annual Report, July 1975-June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - ICED- Annual Report, July 1976- June 1977 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - ICED Seminar- Aspen Institute, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - ICED Seminar- Aspen Institute, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - ICED Seminar-Aspen Institute, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - ICED Seminar- Aspen Institute, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - ICED Financial Report, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - ICED- Letters of thanks for ICED publications, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - International Education (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Williamsburg Conference-Planning Conference, February 1967 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Vice-Chancellor's Conference- Ibadan, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Report of the External Advisory Panel on Education to the World Bank, October 31, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Analytic Comparison of Educational Systems- Overview of Purposes, Policies, Structures and Outcomes, February 1982 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - The Consequences of Higher Education (various papers) (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Bellagio Conference on Higher Education, July 25-29, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Council on Foreign Relations Committee on Studies (member 1965-69; 1974-79 and chairman 1976-79), 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The International Council for Educational Development (miscellaneous papers), 1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Series V. Miscellaneous personal papers (Letters, invitations, interviews, honorary degrees, clippings)
  - Special Letters (i.e. President Lyndon B. Johnson) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Personal Letters, 1943-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Travel Reviews, 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Invitations and Menus, 1959-1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Eric Ashby, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Stuart M. Brown, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Maria Gornikiewicz, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bill Marvel, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Teacher Insurance and Annuity Association of American-College Retirement Equities Fund- Oral History Project, September 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York- Interview No. 2, May 27, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Interview with Dr. James Perkins in his office at 20 Nassau Street, Princeton, NJ (interviewer was Keith Johnson), December 16, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Centre College, Commencement (Honorary Degree), June 8, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Case Institute of Technology, Commencement (Honorary Degree), June 13, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - University of Akron, Founders Day (Honorary Degree), December 13, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ohio University (Honorary Degree), May 11, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Brown University (Honorary Degree), June 3, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Rutgers University (Honorary Degree), June 5, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Swarthmore College Commencement (Honorary Degree), June 10, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Syracuse University Commencement (Honorary Degree), June 7, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Lehigh University (Honorary Degree), June 8, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Northwestern University Commencement (Honorary Degree), June 13, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Princeton University Commencement (Honorary Degree), June 16, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Rochester University (Honorary Degree), June 6, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - University of Toronto (Honorary Degree), November 26, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Long Island University (Honorary Degree), February 2, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Columbia University (Honorary Degree), June 1, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Hamilton College (Honorary Degree), June 5, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - University of Illinois (Honorary Degree), May 5, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - University of Pennsylvania (Honorary Degree), May 22, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - State University of New York at Binghamton (Honorary Degree), May 25, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - University of Notre Dame (Honorary Degree), June 2, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Yale University (Honorary Degree), June 10, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Yeshiva University (Honorary Degree), June 13, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - University of Sydney (Honorary Degree), August 21, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - University of Maine (Honorary Degree), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - University of Florida (Honorary Degree), February 14, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Performing Arts Center (Cornell University), 1985 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Newspaper articles, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - 1992 Events (Cornell University), 1992 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Cornell Commencement Meeting (Cornell University), 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Perkins Prize/ Tom Jones Correspondence (Cornell University), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    Includes copy of a 1978 letter sent to Perkins from President of Oberlin College Robert Fuller about increasing enrollment of black students, Perkins had forwarded this letter in 1995 to Robert Miller.
  - Cornell University oral history, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Perkins Prize, April 1997 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Important Quotes (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Important/Amusing articles (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Congressional Record- Senate, July 12, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Defense Advisory Committee on Education in the Armed Forces (Award), 1964 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 7)
    Contents include a picture passport, two caps and tassels, a Cornell guest book as well as the numerous honorary degrees, which Perkins received from colleges and universities across the country
  - Certificates and diplomas (Folder 1)